<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rainmatter Foundation</title><link>https://rainmatter.org/</link><description>Recent content on Rainmatter Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://rainmatter.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About us</title><link>https://rainmatter.org/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rainmatter.org/about/</guid><description>Rainmatter Foundation is an initiative by the people behind Zerodha. We realise that climate change is the biggest existential threat to life as we know it, and we have committed to using the resources available to us to enable, and to attempt to replicate at scale, the potential solutions that may help address at least some of these threats, and aid in the restoration of our natural ecosystems.
We are a non-profit that aims to support grassroots individuals and organisations engaged in solving these problems, as well as startups working on entrepreneurship that helps scale ideas around in the space.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://rainmatter.org/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rainmatter.org/contact/</guid><description>I can be reached at kailash@nadh.in</description></item><item><title>Funding</title><link>https://rainmatter.org/funding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rainmatter.org/funding/</guid><description>Startups We not only think climate change is an urgent and critical issue to address, but that businesses and economies need to align with this direction. That there is an opportunity for smart entrepreneurs to create businesses around this that are profitable and have positive impacts on the planet.
We invest in startups working in this area via our investment company, Rainmatter Capital. If you are a startup or organisation working in this area and are looking for funding, introduce your organisation on the forum and we will get in touch with you.</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>https://rainmatter.org/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rainmatter.org/projects/</guid><description>Both re-wilding as well as the creation of a green economy need a deep understanding of the conditions and reality on the ground, and committed local changemakers to engage with stakeholders there. Providing direct funding and support to individuals and organisations working on the ground, and ensuring that the solutions they create are documented and made available to many more, is core to what we do.
If you are an organisation working in this area, you can appply for funding or to our small grants program.</description></item><item><title>Research</title><link>https://rainmatter.org/research/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rainmatter.org/research/</guid><description>I obtained a PhD (2009 - 2011) in Artificial Intelligence &amp;amp; Computational Linguistics from the Middlesex University, London, under Dr. Christian Huyck.
My thesis—“Modelling Emergent Phenomena in Associative Memory with Neural Cell Assemblies”—dealt (PDF) with the dynamics of associative memories modeled in in neural Cell Assemblies. The work involved creating Hebbian Cell Assembly models investigating natural language processing, simulated vision, spatial cognitive mapping, queriable hierarchical memories, self-learning agents, and more.</description></item><item><title>Small grants program</title><link>https://rainmatter.org/grants/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rainmatter.org/grants/</guid><description>Small grants CSR Funding typically tends to be focused on short to medium term projects. Many small organizations and teams are working on ideas with a longer term impact and that may be focused on advocacy, education, research or capacity building, rather than direct outcomes.
Ar Rainmatter Foundation, we believe that these are important directions to pursue over time and would like to enable and support such organizations and teams to continue their work on spaces that are part of our circle of concern, across projects and ideas, and with sustained focus over time.</description></item></channel></rss>