<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rainmatter Foundation</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on Rainmatter Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About us</title><link>/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/</guid><description>Founded in 2021, we are a non-profit organisation that supports organisations and projects for climate action, a healthier environment, and livelihoods associated with them. We recognise that climate change is the biggest existential threat to life as we know it. We have committed to using the resources available to us to enable, and to attempt to replicate at scale, the potential solutions that may help address at least some of these threats, and aid in the restoration of our natural ecosystems.</description></item><item><title>Focus Areas</title><link>/focus-areas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/focus-areas/</guid><description>Finding solutions to the climate problem needs a deep understanding of ground realities and committed local changemakers to engage with local stakeholders. We forge partnerships and provide support which may include but is not limited to direct funding to organisations, individuals and alliances working at different areas of an entire spectrum through grants, fellowships and investments.
We look at our work along the following thesis areas.
Conservation The Foundation seeks to address India&amp;rsquo;s conservation and restoration opportunities and challenges through a collaborative approach.</description></item><item><title>Partnerships, grants, and investments</title><link>/partners/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/partners/</guid><description>Both re-wilding as well as the creation of a green economy need a deep understanding of ground realities and committed local changemakers to engage with local stakeholders. We forge partnerships and provide direct funding and support to organisations working at different areas of an entire spectrum. If you are an organisation working in this space and would like to partner with us, please write to us at info@rainmatter.org.
Grants {{ investments(type=&amp;quot;grants&amp;rdquo;) }}</description></item><item><title>Research</title><link>/research/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/research/</guid><description>I obtained a PhD (2009 - 2011) in Artificial Intelligence &amp;amp; Computational Linguistics from the Middlesex University, London, under Dr. Christian Huyck.
My thesis—“Modelling Emergent Phenomena in Associative Memory with Neural Cell Assemblies”—dealt (PDF) with the dynamics of associative memories modeled in in neural Cell Assemblies. The work involved creating Hebbian Cell Assembly models investigating natural language processing, simulated vision, spatial cognitive mapping, queriable hierarchical memories, self-learning agents, and more.</description></item><item><title>Resources</title><link>/resources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/resources/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Terms and Conditions</title><link>/disclosure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/disclosure/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The No Corporate Gift Box Pledge</title><link>/no-gift-pledge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/no-gift-pledge/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Place Lens: Care &amp; Concern with Trade-offs</title><link>/place-thesis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/place-thesis/</guid><description>As a species we’re problem solvers. We solve problems at every level of society, multiple times every day. We make choices, and as we make those, we make trade-offs. Increasingly over the last few centuries we have done this in ever narrower silos and as specialists optimizing for “our” variables at the cost of many others.
For a bit now the dominant lens to view the world through has been through trade, GDP numbers and those that fuelled these - the market and economy view of things.</description></item></channel></rss>