<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rainmatter Foundation</title><link>https://rainmatter.org/</link><description>Recent content on Rainmatter Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://rainmatter.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About us</title><link>https://rainmatter.org/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rainmatter.org/about/</guid><description>Founded in 2021, we are a non-profit organisation that supports organisations and projects for climate action, a healthier environment, and livelihoods associated with them. We recognise that climate change is the biggest existential threat to life as we know it. We have committed to using the resources available to us to enable, and to attempt to replicate at scale, the potential solutions that may help address at least some of these threats, and aid in the restoration of our natural ecosystems.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://rainmatter.org/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rainmatter.org/contact/</guid><description>I can be reached at kailash@nadh.in</description></item><item><title>Partnerships, grants, and investments</title><link>https://rainmatter.org/partners/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rainmatter.org/partners/</guid><description>Both re-wilding as well as the creation of a green economy need a deep understanding of ground realities and committed local changemakers to engage with local stakeholders. We forge partnerships and provide direct funding and support to organisations working at different areas of an entire spectrum. If you are an organisation working in this space and would like to partner with us, please write to us at info@rainmatter.org.
Grants 2025 The Local Food Project (Locavore) The Locavore is a platform committed to creating enduring impact through food.</description></item><item><title>Research</title><link>https://rainmatter.org/research/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rainmatter.org/research/</guid><description>I obtained a PhD (2009 - 2011) in Artificial Intelligence &amp;amp; Computational Linguistics from the Middlesex University, London, under Dr. Christian Huyck.
My thesis—“Modelling Emergent Phenomena in Associative Memory with Neural Cell Assemblies”—dealt (PDF) with the dynamics of associative memories modeled in in neural Cell Assemblies. The work involved creating Hebbian Cell Assembly models investigating natural language processing, simulated vision, spatial cognitive mapping, queriable hierarchical memories, self-learning agents, and more.</description></item><item><title>Resources for Sustainable Lifestyle</title><link>https://rainmatter.org/resources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rainmatter.org/resources/</guid><description>Zero Waste Offices The plastic cup nonchalantly tossed in the bin by the water filter has by now made its way to a landfill on the outskirts of the city. The confetti at the end of the celebration is flowing alongside our waters into the closest river. The tiniest particles of plastic are a part of our systems as much as the air we breathe. It is out of our sight in a second, but it impacts our lives forever.</description></item><item><title>Terms and Conditions</title><link>https://rainmatter.org/disclosure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rainmatter.org/disclosure/</guid><description>General 1.1These terms and conditions (“Terms”) contain important information regarding Rainmatter Foundation (“Foundation”) and your use of this website. The Terms govern the relationship between us and you, the user (“You”). 1.2The Website is owned, operated and maintained by Rainmatter Foundation, a Section-8 Company incorporated under the Companies Act 2013, having its registered office at #153/154, 4th Cross, Dollars Colony, JP Nagar 4th Phase, Bangalore - 560078. 1.3These Terms shall govern the relationship between the Foundation and You.</description></item><item><title>The No Corporate Gift Box Pledge</title><link>https://rainmatter.org/no-gift-pledge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rainmatter.org/no-gift-pledge/</guid><description>The page template is in ~/layouts/give/single.html The data lists are ~/data/no-gift-donees.yml and ~/data/no-gift-pledgers.yml</description></item><item><title>Thesis</title><link>https://rainmatter.org/thesis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rainmatter.org/thesis/</guid><description>Finding solutions to the climate problem needs a deep understanding of ground realities and committed local changemakers to engage with local stakeholders. We forge partnerships and provide support which may include but is not limited to direct funding to organisations, individuals and alliances working at different areas of an entire spectrum through grants, fellowships and investments.
We look at our work along the following thesis areas.
Conservation The Foundation seeks to address India&amp;rsquo;s conservation and restoration opportunities and challenges through a collaborative approach.</description></item></channel></rss>