<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rainmatter Foundation</title><link>https://rainmatter.org/</link><description>Recent content on Rainmatter Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://rainmatter.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About us</title><link>https://rainmatter.org/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rainmatter.org/about/</guid><description>Founded in 2019, we are a non-profit organisation that supports organisations and projects for climate action, a healthier environment, and livelihoods associated with them. We recognise that climate change is the biggest existential threat to life as we know it. We have committed to using the resources available to us to enable, and to attempt to replicate at scale, the potential solutions that may help address at least some of these threats, and aid in the restoration of our natural ecosystems.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://rainmatter.org/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rainmatter.org/contact/</guid><description>I can be reached at kailash@nadh.in</description></item><item><title>Funding and grants</title><link>https://rainmatter.org/funding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rainmatter.org/funding/</guid><description>Our focus areas Rewilding - More Forest Everywhere — Your organisation works on or encourages direct rewilding of spaces, or encourages better soil management and biodiversity at farms, in public spaces and the commons in turn making every space a little more forest-like.
Resilient Ecosystems, Conservation and Restoration — Your organisation works to tackle air pollution, responsibly manages water resources, or is engaged in other similar domains.</description></item><item><title>Partnerships, grants, and investments</title><link>https://rainmatter.org/partners/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rainmatter.org/partners/</guid><description>Both re-wilding as well as the creation of a green economy need a deep understanding of ground realities and committed local changemakers to engage with local stakeholders. We forge partnerships and provide direct funding and support to organisations working at different areas of an entire spectrum. If you are an organisation working in this space and would like to partner with us, please write to us at info@rainmatter.org.
Investments 2023 Ossus Bio Ossus has developed an intelligent bioreactor, the OB HydraCel, which accesses carbon in the wastewater from process industries and supplies these industries with on-demand, on-site hydrogen gas.</description></item><item><title>Research</title><link>https://rainmatter.org/research/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rainmatter.org/research/</guid><description>I obtained a PhD (2009 - 2011) in Artificial Intelligence &amp;amp; Computational Linguistics from the Middlesex University, London, under Dr. Christian Huyck.
My thesis—“Modelling Emergent Phenomena in Associative Memory with Neural Cell Assemblies”—dealt (PDF) with the dynamics of associative memories modeled in in neural Cell Assemblies. The work involved creating Hebbian Cell Assembly models investigating natural language processing, simulated vision, spatial cognitive mapping, queriable hierarchical memories, self-learning agents, and more.</description></item><item><title>The No Corporate Gift Box Pledge</title><link>https://rainmatter.org/no-gift-pledge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rainmatter.org/no-gift-pledge/</guid><description>The page template is in ~/layouts/give/single.html The data lists are ~/data/no-gift-donees.yml and ~/data/no-gift-pledgers.yml</description></item></channel></rss>